[Music]
good morning good evening good afternoon
wherever you are in the world thank you
so much for tuning in and joining us for
a special stream should be available on
the BB YouTube crash's YouTube channel
and both of our X accounts we are doing
a special Market discussion and ta
collaboration my name is Max I'm the CEO
of because Bitcoin joined by a friend
goes by crashes clay oops hang on sorry
I had the YouTube up in the background
joined by a friend named crashes clay we
got a lot to discuss today I put a funny
little background on here
um this is the it's over picture it's a
very layered Meme here at because
Bitcoin but a lot of you guys that have
been around for a while know what this
means it's a meme it's just gauging
sentiment but anyways the last time that
crash and I did a stream together was
maybe a few months ago give or take we
come in with no plan and we both just
talk about what we're seeing in the
markets and usually we both learn
something we have fun and of course at
the same time you guys learn something
and have fun so that's the strategy for
today a lot of charts a lot of
discussions crash recently dropped a
video with some of his thoughts on
perhaps where us equities are at
contextually um I guess locally and also
on the higher time frames potentially I
have some thoughts I didn't catch the
whole video but I have seen the analysis
we're going to talk about that and then
some of my thoughts for us equities and
then also crypto as we head deeper into
Q4 um and get really close to the
election so anyways guys before we get
too far into it do a is solid let's get
this out of the way right away if you're
excited hit that like button subscribe
to both of our our YouTube channels and
X accounts if you don't already I'm sure
that you guys do share the content call
a friend call your grandma call your mom
call your dad call your mailman they
need to see this all right show some
love we're gonna have a great time today
I don't know how long we're going to go
for I feel like last time we said an
hour and we went for like two and a half
so we're just going to roll with the
punches and see where it goes but crash
bro happy we got to do this again it's
been a long time a lot of price action
um a lot of price action has occurred
since we last did this so lots to talk
about and update people on but how are
you bro how you
been I'm good just slightly concerned
about where the stock market is at and
we'll go over but every single September
and October the stock market tops going
into the election and so you know just
obviously the last two times that
happened Bitcoin was unaffected so hope
Bitcoin will be unaffected by that but
obviously Bitcoin has ETFs now and that
may actually make us more tied to the
stock market we don't know yet you know
so let's see yeah that's a really it's a
really interesting debate to have like
has Bitcoin kind of merged with Legacy
Finance in a way because of these new
vehicles that allow you to actually get
direct exposure to spot Bitcoin through
these ETFs and now eth right we are kind
of being gobbled up by uh these goliaths
within Legacy Finance but here's what we
should do man how about you pull up your
chart first we got you down below maybe
just walk us through like what are you
seeing right now let's go over I mean I
know we probably need to discuss your
most recent um local prediction on
stocks I'm sure a lot of people are
going to want to see us go back and
forth about that um but yeah let's talk
about stocks and crypto like just frame
the market for us bro like what are you
seeing right now yeah so check this out
I know you're in the camp of the dollar
is going to break down and then the Bull
Run begins right and so recently right
the dollar was just coming down for
months right from April down to this was
October and so right here everyone
thinks that the dollar is going to break
down and instead right and and you know
big reason reason why the dollar is
going down is probably because
everyone's what front running and
anticipating that the US would lower
interest rates so that makes the dollar
weaker but then once they actually raise
the interest I'm sorry lower the
interest rate and everyone thinks that
the Market's going to break down or at
least the dollar I mean you know what
does it do it actually bottoms and it
starts pumping from here and so we had
bullish Divergence there on daily comes
down to the bottom of the range everyone
in the world and their mothers thinks
that the bull run like the the beautiful
part of it that where everything just
goes up only it was going to happen like
right here right and here we are we're
about to go up because like basically if
dollar drops like from there from you
know 100 down to 92 for example that's
your bull run and then bam it doesn't
happen instead we get this bullish
Divergence and we're pumping from there
and so right now that's your bottom in
the dollar and if that's your bottom in
the dollar it's usually you know Bitcoin
and the market is going to go the
opposite way of that and so basically I
think the bottom in the dollar is right
there for now and then obviously I think
that the the stock market is topped
right here at
5820 and I think we're going to see it
pull back at four to
eight% but the thing is man you look at
this chart and you know okay the last
pullbacks in the stock market were 7%
this pullback here was 10% so this one 4
to 8% minimum and you just got to hope
that stock uh um crypto doesn't move
with the stock market because you know
typically if the stock market dips 10%
you're going to see crypto dip 20% for
example and in that case you know if
crypto continue moving with the stock
market you know 20% dip there for
Bitcoin would take us down to that low
again right which is like 48k and
obviously none of us want to see that
what we want to see is the dollar breaks
down and the Golden Bull Run that
everyone's waiting for starts you know
but it's not as simple as everyone
always thinks right and so once again
everyone thinks the dollar is going to
break down buom Market is going to begin
and it's actually the bottom for the
dollar right there right now and there's
really no reason for us to go below that
low in the dollar at the moment you know
especially when you consider that every
single September and October stock
market tops going into the election and
also by the way look at this pattern
right here that we're doing in the S&P
500 so over here this this was all-time
highs right and uh this was going into
2022 so you had the same exact pattern
where you had this first drive higher
come down second Drive higher come down
and that third Drive higher overshoots
those first two tops meanwhile you have
bearish Divergence and you have
declining volume on the way up right
here so check this out this pattern
right here is like literally exactly
what we're doing right now you had top
one top two and those those two moves
lower as well and then you have this
third Drive higher which slightly
overshoots those two tops and then you
have once again bearish Divergence so to
me by the way you also have the the
bearish declining volume less than less
buyers are coming in as we go higher
here into once again all what always
happens is going into election you have
major dips in September and October in
the stock market it makes a lot of sense
you have the same pattern repeating
right here you have that same exact
pattern repeating right here okay and it
just makes sense for example when you're
at all-time highs going into an election
where it's very 5050 right it's very
close who's going to win for example if
you're holding solar stocks or you're
holding oil stocks those price movements
are going to be very dependent on who
wins that election so is it feel safe
and smart to hold you know if you if
you're all in on oil does it make sense
to
you know a ton of oil if Camala wins for
example that could you know send those
oil stocks lower for example and so or
if you hold solar and you you want to
camalo win would you hold the solar
stocks if Trump's winning or are they
probably going to see a decline or you
know shortterm the price action and
reaction to that could bearish right if
Trump won instead of Kamala so it just
makes sense when you're at all-time high
going into election that you want to
risk going into a very political thing
where you know the the prices of so many
Industries depends on that election you
know what I mean so it just makes sense
to drisk going into election and I think
that's why you know there's so much
uncertainty going into election who's
going to win that's why you see them
unload their positions always in
September October before the election
and then a lot of times they just buy
back after the election so anyways when
you have this pattern repeating again
you have bearish Divergence bearish uh
lesson L volume coming in and you have
the perfect time to drisk before the
election I think this is the perfect
setup for a local top at the very least
the stock market you
know so I've seen a couple different
things from you so I agree like for
one pattern recognition is the secret to
to trading right A lot of people don't
believe in fractals they're like oh it
just does you can't properly apply
context it doesn't work like finding
your Edge is really just a matter of
screen time and saying I've seen this
before there's a certain probability not
a guarantee but a probability that this
will happen again because conditions
rhyme right so I think it's it's solid
to recognize that hey we've potentially
set a deviation like a shallow deviation
with a bearish Divergence with low or
like falling volume in price Discovery
for SPX where have we seen this before
but let's just get one one thing super
clear like are you suggesting this is a
local drisking spot for an October sell
for us equities or potentially the start
of a multi-year downtrend like we saw in
2022 yeah so that's the thing when you
have the pattern right if we uh if you
just dragged and dropped the pattern
which where is this thing dude is over
somewhere over here Mars
yeah right there yeah so and and if you
actually overlay
that um right here wait no I I drew that
wrong it's from this part to there like
you know that's that's what I'm saying
we don't know the severity of a drop we
just know that hey the same exact
topping pattern is there right like it's
it's exactly the same you see it we're
following that to the te you see that I
I potentially see it I see no it's
literally the exact same bro it's it's
not different at all and so when you
have the same topping pattern that led
us to you know a year of
decline um you know all I know see
here's the thing I can't know the length
of decline I can't know how severe the
decline I can just know with confidence
I believe that this is a top now where
does that top take us to how low does it
take us to I don't know right now right
like when I shorted Bitcoin at 69k I
knew that that was a top locally at the
very least right but I I couldn't know
with absolute certainty that you're
going to go to 15K from 69k right and so
whenever you short a top it's a
different thing than knowing where that
you know where it takes you fully you
know what I mean ahead of time so all I
have confidence in right now is that
that's top and but here's the thing
usually um if you look at the last
elections right what happens for the S&P
okay so it tops in September and October
going into the election right and then
bam it's falling into the election and
then right after the election in
November bam up only from there right so
you can see the election hits it goes up
only okay let's go back to the other
time and so pretty much the last three
times for the S SMP
um it was just up only after okay and I
guess I didn't uh map out all these
times yet on this specific chart it must
have been on another one but okay over
here once again you see Sharp drop going
into the election in
October you know it dumps 9% going into
election right this is the peak of
October and then bam right here is the
end of October and then bam look
November hits the election hits up only
right so that's 2020 that's 2016 if we
go back to
2012 once again you
see
2012 September October look this is
September right yeah um you're topping
in
September right you're topping in
October again and now let's zoom in
because I know it's a little small for
everyone so September October right what
does it do look Market is at not
all-time highs right but it's at its
Highs at the at the moment there in that
last year or two so it's at its highs
right and then September October tops
going into the election and look
election hits in November and it's up
only from there okay so
2012 uh 2016 and 2020 same [__] happens
every time top in September October top
in September October fall into the
election once the election comes prices
save it goes up on from there but then
if you work your way back to now
2008 okay same this is the cool thing
this is the main thing I wanted to point
out to people is that every time in what
September and October what's happening
the market is is you're not making any
money being bullish on the stock market
in the months leading to the election
September October you buy the stock
market in the months leading to election
and look what happens once again
collapses I mean obviously that's 200 8
but it's that's the thing it's not just
2008 where this happens this happened in
every other election year ahead of it so
once again October and it's just down
down only from there and then this in
2008 obviously we're not saved by the
election so it takes a while to recover
there um so yeah I mean that's that's
the major Point that's the major pattern
to notice is like every single time
downward price action comes September
October right right here right here
right here
and right here right 9% drop in October
here of 2020 so that's my whole thing
when you have the same pattern as then
and you have that tendency to set a peak
in October or September going into
election this is the perfect time to
drisk uh from the stock market
perspective and dip right now luckily
for all of us crypto diverges from the
stock market in those months and maybe
you would want to show people that on
your screen where your chart are a lot
more clean and
pretty well you've got some great charts
too but I I would love to comment on
some of this stuff because here's the
thing I I could see a local correction
for SPX all right I just jumped over to
my chart let me know if you need it back
for something we can just kind of go
back and forth I'll take mine off I want
to watch yours okay
so for one you're you're not wrong to
suggest that us equities are in a
potentially vulnerable spot right like
let's obviously this is the example you
were talking about so this was the top
you know last cycle and we kind of had
these these two highs and then you had
this really predatory you know trap up
here and then they sent it down okay now
obviously with fractals context is key
because at this same time here the US
was entering the fastest tightening
cycle in regards to interest rates the
effective federal funds rate the fastest
rate hiking cycle that we've ever had
right and this triggered a pretty nasty
correction for us equities that didn't
send us back above alltime highs until
you know 2024 and this top was in 2022
it was basically a two-year bare market
right and it was catalyzed of course by
something that was horrible and a lot of
shock you know surprise 50 and 75 basis
point hikes that spooked the markets and
of course that was coupled with you know
statistical outlier High year-over-year
us headline CPI I mean back here you
know in the bare Market in
2022 we had us uh CPI over 9% right so
this there was a lot of like economic
factors that in Confluence with this
beautiful little bear trap at the highs
here that catalyzed you know the
momentum actually down right and one
thing here's the thing I'm not trading
equities right now but I do watch them
very closely I think it can be
potentially dangerous to naked short
before any confirmation right I like
that you talked about this example this
right here is back after the covid crash
of 2020 right we had a lot of stimulus
going on they dropped interest rates to
you know historically low levels we were
above the previous all-time high right
here and you saw this same kind of
potential trap right here where you know
you you you put in this this kind of
weird like you know one two drive down
potential deviation up and the economy
was still largely shut down at this
point right like Co was still very much
so gripping our economy and people I
remember I was actively trading during
this time like they were like oh run
this back you know like this is we're
not going to go much higher than this um
but then of course like shorting too
early led to you know it was just a
continuous grind up right because things
weren't breaking they were actually
improving like the economy was shut down
but there was so much
manufacturing of you know I guess bull
market conditions with dirt cheap money
um and even though we had higher
unemployment we had this sort of
Goldilocks window of stimulus where they
effectively doubled our monetary uh base
and the M2 money supply within like an
18month period so I think it's just
important to recognize and I know that
you do like there's a lot of these
little like bear traps that that can get
set you know over and over and over
again and it's just it's an extremely
difficult thing to do and then even like
right here before the all-time high like
this this looked terrible right here
right you know we could easily look at
this and go yeah that's your deviation
oh and look you know we broke our kind
of Normy diagonal Trend this thing is
cooked you know and then it just starts
moving back up so calling a top on
equities like for one it's a very very
tough thing to do right I actually
personally like to wait for as much
possible confirmation as I Poss possibly
can get for equities because if you want
to talk about a manipulated Ponzi there
is no greater manipulated Ponzi in the
entire world than the S&P 500 they
manufacture this thing to go up right if
you look at this thing on the weekly
time frame I mean it's it looks like a
shitcoin I mean look at this thing this
is why all of our parents have so much
money if they've been mindlessly dcing
into their 401ks because it's just
manipulated right like they don't let it
fail oh co happens the economy shuts
down they double the money supply
there's no reason we should have done
this right but I see the pattern you're
talking about but I like to just be as
careful as I can like I mean for example
if we're talking about stocks here
specifically okay um I like to wait for
a real high time frame breakup Trend
even if that means I'm slightly late to
the move you know I would rather wait
for you know you have this long barrel
of bullishness right it's just like a
mechanical twap upwards right they're
just burning any put premiums um and
this thing rips and then I'd rather
personally look to to short like the
confirmed break of structure like this
no new all-time high and then you know
buy some long-dated puts and you know
start targeting lower levels like that
like I like to wait for as much because
it's so tough to call a top and if you
do it like God bless you you know that's
not exactly something that I I feel
super comfortable with um you know and
for me that high time frame trend is
probably more like right here you know
could we talk you know could we zoom in
and say locally you know we have this
you know this little trend line right
here if this breaks you know could we
visit the lower one yeah we could but I
am not super confident in saying like
your Global top is in just because I
know how manipulated this thing is and
how many little bear traps they
constantly set but you're not wrong in
my opinion to recognize you know very
obvious signs of momentum dwindling
which could be you know this September
October seasonality especially leading
into an uncertain time which is the
election we're seeing bives printing on
kind of the mid time frames mid to
higher time frames volume is is you know
declining a little bit and we're just
kind of floating above the all-time high
but for me it's a little bit early one
other thing that I think you know really
helps me view this is I like to look at
the vix okay
so when times are
uncertain you typically get like a vix
blowout right so people are buying you
know vix calls where you can see if we
overlay these together you can see the
vix perfectly lines up with like every
major drop right they have a negative
correlation okay every big drop you know
the the premium on these vix calls
assuming most people are playing them uh
to hedge for downside volatility you
know these begin to really print when
you get a bad piece of economic data or
a bare market and you can see how a lot
of these drops for the S&P 500 happen I
mean all of them as the Vic starts to
blow out okay we just recently had one
so let's let's take a look at a
couple examples
here so going all the way back let's
look at the weekly time frame we'll put
the S&P 500 in log mode actually I need
more data than this let's just put up
SX we're going to go back a little bit
further okay so we'll get rid of
this oops I don't know what move to New
pain above I didn't mean to do that okay
so the S&P 500 is above and the vix is
below so typically what we'll see after
like a vix blowout like this one and by
the way the Vick Spike that we had you
know when we were having uh we had
basically our surprise us unemployment
print in October when it it was expected
at like 39 and it came in at 4.3 that
was bad right that was bad um but we
haven't seen the vix blow out to you
know to levels like this really ever
there's only a handful of times right in
recent years you know
2008 um covid and then just recently
right when we had that surprise
unemployment print and I think there was
like US dollar JPY fears right like
Japan basically liquidated liquidated
itself in Trader terms okay but what you
typically see after a vix blowout like
that is you'll get you know pretty nasty
drop obviously this one was a multi-year
recession catalyzed by uh the housing
cred here in the US where um basically
Banks were engaging in predatory lending
practices with variable rate notes and
when these interest rates began to rise
people couldn't afford to pay their
mortgages but what you typically see
after a vix blowout is a long period of
like kind of compression right where
you'll have these little pullbacks and
things like that but you'll see the vix
just get crushed and crushed and crushed
after the blowout and then you just get
this like big big move up up you know
and then you'll have another blowout
when you finally kind of break that
trend line for the vix and then you get
you know another pull back here and then
you know look what happened over here we
had our vixs blow out because of covid
and then you basically just saw you know
this giant compression right here I
probably looks better in log just so you
can actually see it you had your vix
blowout because of covid and then you
just had V premiums just getting crushed
the entire time and then we had our
blowout right here now some will say
like oh that wasn't big enough enough
well I mean I guess I don't make the
rules you know we had a vix blowout to a
level that's comparable to the dot
crisis and the great financial crisis
the dotcom bubble collapse and the great
financial crisis and in my view it's
more likely that we're going to do what
we've always done with the vix and just
see volatility just get crushed again
and before we have another like big you
know bare Market or something like that
we're going to just see like you know
volatility get crushed and you could
even look at it more like this and say
you know look at actually what
cused look at what you know look look at
how this called the top right you had
your covid volatility blowout right here
for the vixs and then you basically saw
the Vicks just get crushed you know
trend line rejection rejection rejection
rejection and then right up here what
did we see we saw the Vick starting to
break out and then of course that was
your top right so I'm not it's never
happened before where you've had a Vick
Spike to 60 followed by another giant
Vick Spike to 60 within like recent
months in my view it's it's more likely
going to do this like lower highs drop
Market goes up lower high Market goes up
and you're just gonna you're going to
enter one of these like grind higher
type of scenarios um and additionally on
top of that I'm not seeing the Catalyst
right now for some major risk off event
in equities personally right like if
you're seeing it like we can talk about
it but if we're going to enter a
recession this would be the first time
that we've ever seen a major recession
in the US where everybody still had a
job I mean if you look at the uh
us us unemployment
rate go to the
Daily we are at historically low levels
for us unemployment like us unemployment
came in this morning under expectations
we had a really solid print at
4.1% okay so typically when you have
these recessions you'll start to see
unemployment actually like curling up
all right here's us unemployment we'll
just ignore covid because that was you
know three or four standard deviation
move away from our mean but what you'll
typically see is you'll actually see
unemployment you know creeping up like
for multiple months begin to actually
print like higher numbers and then you
get a big riskof event so what we're
seeing right here is actually the
opposite like we've seen kind of a
normalization of our labor market here
in the US um but you're not going to get
some major risk-off event if people have
jobs that's usually the last Domino to
fall is like initial jobless claims
people claiming unemployment for
benefits start to climb and then you'll
start to see you know year-over-year
unemployment Spike and that's just
simply not what we're seeing like both
of these you know major sell-offs back
here in um you know right back here in
in 20
up which is what we look like we're
doing now too no but we're not we just
the two previous prints were lower so we
had 43 in August and then 42 and today
41 so it's actually trending down look
at those last two ones in December and
April you have pointed out they both had
lower lower prints well depends where
you put your black line but they both
had a Lower Print before they went much
higher you see what I'm saying
so I would say I would just I would
remain dated so like I was talking with
my guys this morning and I was like if
we get a US unemployment print the
expectation this morning was 4.2 I said
if we get like a 4.4 we're trending up
you know we're we're trending up that's
a problem so whether the data is
manipulated because there's an election
coming up I don't I'm not really of the
opinion that they do that but maybe it
was politically motivated we're trending
down the previous two prints were
trending down so if we start to get data
that's suggests like we are trending up
then I say it's pretty obvious what's
about to happen you know then you're
going to get a major risk-off event but
I don't think you can get a major
risk-off event that doesn't mean you
can't get a correction like for example
right over here in last October which
I'll put up the Bitcoin example for this
as well you had unemployment under 4%
and you had a giant seasonal correction
you know from July all the way through
basically the end of October where the
S&P 500 did dipped almost 12% and we had
record low unemployment so you could get
a local technical correction but in
terms of like a you know a multi-year
recession mainly calling for is a 4 to
eight% correction going into the
election and then I'm praying that it
doesn't turn into something much worse
and bigger than a 4 to eight% correction
because here's the thing man if you're
looking at data prints um you know by
the time the data starts looking bad the
Market's already began its descent lower
so data is lagging to the market almost
always I feel like so the reality is if
you're going to anticipate a market drop
of course later on it's going to start
crashing when the when the data starts
coming in bad you know what I mean so
usually to be honest good data is more
likely to happen closer to a top than on
the way down anyways you know so to me I
don't really worry about that data the
short term because at the end of the day
when Bitcoin is at 69k everyone was
talking about how incredible and how
bullish everything is and how good the
data is all around the board and
everything is so good and well when
everything is so good when the data is
so good it's usually that's when you're
actually closer to the top so to me I'm
just looking based off the pattern which
by the way the pattern you showed in
2020 which I also have on my chart which
is when Joe Biden won the election that
is the same pattern as now so God
willing from my net worth and yours and
everyone watching hopefully that's
exactly what we get you know if you want
to go back and show that example in 2020
like that would be a dream come true
because I'm going to lose my ass if we
if we drop probably you know um or if we
drop more than eight% in the stock
market like if it actually ends up being
something bad um and so yeah are you
talking about right in here yeah right
there yeah exactly right there that's
the same pattern as now pretty much and
so we could get that too and you know
God willing we do because I'm all in
Long besides this little head short I
have you know and so I can easily see
that playing out too but my main thing
though is I do think okay in that
example what happened from the peak of
October the market dumped like what what
is that eight nine% right so that's what
I think is going to happen at the least
and then once again if you know
everything is good you know hopefully
Trump wins and we go up only just like
they're in 2020 after that you know but
I think people do underestimate that
there's a real chance that you know what
like I said what am I confident in that
I believe there's a top at 5800 and we
get a 4 to 8% drop and so as long as
it's just a 4 to eight% drop well based
on 2020 2016 2012 crypto was just fine
so as long as this top if I'm right even
that it's a top in the stock market
which I do think it is right but that's
the thing I I put it in tweet I've put
it a bunch of times I'm like this I
believe it's a local top in stocks and
we just need to pray that it doesn't
turn into something more severe because
here's the thing you know how many
people call the top in the stock market
or Bitcoin and stuff very little and a
big reason because of that is because
everyone thinks everything is so good
and they think no way it could ever top
here and of course that's where it does
top at 69,000 Bitcoin nobody almost
nobody would thought it could top there
because everyone thought it was going
100K and right now also nobody thinks it
could top and it could top man it it
never tops when it's obvious first off
right and right now is a very not
obvious time to talk there were some
okay I would say it wasn't super obvious
right like I I'll be honest I was bold
up in the upper 60s like when we got
back above 64k I was like it's time for
100k you know and I started to drisk
down in this region right probably like
early
2022 but there were some serious
concerns because of this bottom chart
here so SPX is up top Bitcoin in the
middle and then US inflation rate
year-over-year is down below you can see
that you know as soon as covid hit right
here and they started stimulating and
printing a ton of money they basically
doubled our our money supply during this
time period you saw at the 69k top US
year-over-year inflation went from like
nothing basically to over 7% right and
those that of course study you know
history of these markets recognize that
and Bitcoin doesn't go back that far
typically when you get really high
inflation there has to be some sort of
like cutting cycle or hiking to cutting
cycle that happens where then if we add
you know the effective federal funds
rate down below you can see that they
started cutting rates here and you know
we had really High inflation so it was
kind of this like and actually people
were losing their jobs over here too but
it's important to contextualize like
what is the the reason behind some of
this stuff right like I I love the
fractals I do but you know this was this
was a cause for concern right not that I
took heed to it right in hindsight it's
easy to say SPX was topped right
here look at when Bitcoin topped and
look at where US inflation was right it
was on the rise and so the reality
is inflation was at six and a half when
Bitcoin topped roughly and the US Target
is
2% right but inflation's on the rise
it's on the rise here you know so the
only way inflation numbers would have
helped you actually understand anything
here is if you go back and look at
history and then you see okay when
inflation gets above what 7% That's when
it's bad you know what I mean but the
reality is Bitcoin topped before the
inflation numbers hit that you know so
in this case to me this shows that
looking at some of these uh data does
not help you predict the top right
because actually Bitcoin topped before
inflation got to where you know it was a
concern so by the time [__] is a concern
the top was already in you
know no that's fair I mean you're right
like if you want to be like if you want
to be not you necessarily but like if
you want to be well in front of these
moves
once the data is out there in the open
it's already been digested by the smart
money like I will 100% agree with you
there you know it's just when we have
inflation trending down to the fed's
longterm Target of 2% which is right
here and this is their long-term Target
like this is where they like to be
around right here is you know just 2%
that's their goal they've been super
clear about
that and you have the cost of capital
actually dropping with the labor market
remaining resilient right so let's put
up the effective federal funds rate
again and we can hide this right here
and we'll put us unemployment back up
like these are the things that typically
Mark the top
is it's what the FED is doing in in
regards to cost of our Capital being the
effective federal funds
rate in tandem with the labor market in
the US because like if people have jobs
you're not getting a recession right
because people they still have money to
spend and they still still have money
that comes out every single week and tws
into the S&P 500 like it just doesn't if
people are employed you're not getting a
recession right so I mean let's even
look back talking about equities here
like look at what happened after we got
our first after we got our first batch
of cuts over here um this was in 2019
like if somebody had said oh they're
cutting rates here in
2019 um you know this this pattern to me
here let's shrink this down a little bit
you know this pattern to me looks scary
right we're you know we're sitting above
the previous all-time high this looks
like a head and shoulders pattern right
head shoulders whatever here's your
little trend line um if you had just
been like oh they're cutting rates and
didn't properly contextualize it like oh
look unemployment is still at three and
a half percent you would have also you
know gotten D again I keep saying you I
don't mean like you specifically I just
mean people in general you know like
there this there's a huge 20% rally
which out of you know us equities index
is huge right we didn't finally start to
see Co until we had emergency Cuts
because they shut the economy down and
we saw unemployment Spike to you know
15% so again you have to be in front of
these moves right you have to be
otherwise this happens really quickly
but I think the most important thing to
do is to contextualize what's actually
happening behind the scenes here right
and the way that I look at it is like
our cost of capital just went down we
just had a 50 basis point cut we're
going to get another couple 25 basis
point Cuts this year I would assume and
the US Labor Market remains resilient I
don't see economic contraction anywhere
I look like GDP is positive actually
came in recently over
expectations cost of capital is going
down um again people have jobs inflation
is trending down to the long-term Target
of 2% China is stimulating right so it's
it's it's important to not look at our
our economy here in the US and just be
like yeah it only matters if the US is
stimulating like there's a lot of
foreign money that enters our Market too
so I'm viewing this right here this
little drop in the effective federal
funds rate as hey this is a mean
reversion cut this is a cut because we
simply can and I hate to even say soft
Landing because it's cringe and it's
overused and people always like to be
like oh we got a soft Landing no
recession like these interest rate hikes
will be felt you know like this right
here when we went from zero to five and
a half
these are going to work their way into
the economy but it's just in my opinion
not here like they feel more like meanor
version Cuts so I don't know I think the
best way to go about it and like I like
your approach is rely on the technicals
and you're seeing this as a potential
vulnerable spot for the S&P 500 my only
thing is I can't get bearish on it until
I see like a high time frame shift
because there's always a complacency
shoulder like even if it means there's
pain right like even if we did this if
you're right and we did this
right there's always going to be that
like huge complacency shoulder to short
there always is like there's this right
here you know we can go back and I guess
Co there wasn't obviously because that
was pretty bizarre but like there's
always a you know a break of structure
and then a big complacency shoulder and
you still can catch the meat of that
move like break of structure there's
your trend line you know and then you
could have shorted any of these highs so
it's like for me I'm I'm going to rely
on the structure right like I'm not
saying you're wrong because like you
seem to call a lot of things pretty damn
spot on
I'm but if you what I'm calling for is a
top into the election and what I said is
best case if we do like 2020 we do like
most of the well the last three election
years what we do is as soon as November
hits boom we're good right stock market
up only from there right I think because
your charts are so nice and clean we
should go over that on your charts real
quick for everyone so everyone can see
Market tops in September October and
then bam once November hits it's just up
only in election years so that's the
thing I think a lot of people are acting
like I'm calling the ultimate collapse
and end of the stock market when that's
not what I'm saying what I'm saying is
that every single time pretty much
you're going to see the stock market
drop in October going into election and
the earliest we see alltime high is 50
days from now which is late o late
November is the earliest be back to
alltime high so I almost even part of me
regrets making anything that's even
slightly bearish because it gets so
overblown but basically what I'm saying
is I believe a local top is in going in
October going into the election and
three out of six ele three of the last
six election years you know it actually
we had a major crashes so basically what
I'm saying I think people are under
estimating uh you know o like super
bullish without even considering that
things could actually be worse than you
think like things could evolve into
worse than just a four point a four to
eight% dip going into election you know
so yeah you can see there you know but
here's the thing okay so everyone who's
watching now on stream This Is 2020 when
Biden wins right this was was 2023 this
was October for this was last October
yeah if you will go back to 2020 later
yeah um you'll see October drops 9% and
Bitcoin was totally fine you know what I
mean so ideally we do the same but my
whole point is is I'm not going to top
as in in the market and if it's last
three times yeah we recover within 50 to
150 days we're back at all-time highs in
the stock market and that means
bitcoin's going hey you know ham but
like I said I just think people are
overlooking the fact that three out of
the last six election years you know
really bad [__] happened and so you know
we could all absolutely be wiped the
[__] out like we could all be destroyed
you know um if things evolved into
something worse than we think and that's
the thing you don't realize it until the
bad you know jobs data is hitting before
all the bad information is hitting you
then you start to realize oh we're
[__] but when you can possibly
anticipate that well in advance I'm I'm
just showing people man like usually we
did 4 to 8% going into the election
that's exactly what I think's going to
happen from there I don't know the
severity right and a lot of the data you
look at would suggest we're going to
recover easily starting in November you
know what I mean yeah last three times
election years we recovered immediately
starting in November but man I feel like
people Overlook that the fact um you
know that three out of six election
years have have turned out badly for us
you know yeah I mean I think a lot of
people I mean a lot of people just
mindlessly DCA in and don't ever even
take note to it so I think it's a really
solid observation and just to be clear
to everybody here like I was just on the
chart you guys were looking at I'm just
highlighting a prime example of yes you
know Bitcoin is becoming more ingrained
in Legacy and and trafi right um now
that institutions are like aici ially
here to play but look at this was 2023
this was actually September and October
which is ironic because that's where
we're at right now um for Bitcoin and
SPX so if crash is correct and like you
get something on the S&P you know like
you drop down this was a deviation and
you bleed SPX bled 99.2% while Bitcoin
was literally ripping face up
42% so just like someone actually tagged
me on Twitter and they're like hey bro
like what do you think about crashes
like SPX thoughts or whatever like
you're think you're bullish crypto and
I'm like we could both be right I don't
really care if the S&P 500 has a local
correction like because I lean into the
technicals which I think we should
transition into like there's a lot of
crypto charts that are screaming up to
me right now um and I think that in your
best case on SPX is probably you just
continue to slowly grind higher where I
think that crypto is more of a beach
ball underwater truthfully kind of like
what we saw last you know Q4 which I'm
highlighting right here um but crash do
you want to talk about some crypto or
should we go over some more Equity stuff
I'm cool with whatever you want to do
well here's what I would say right so
you know in that October S&P dropped 9%
but if it dropped 20% you know obviously
you know Bitcoin would not be going up
like 90% sure that because in 2008 gold
is a safe asset and when 2008 gold
dropped uh you know same with covid when
when covid hit we you know we still drop
right so I would still any major crash
is going to affect everything including
Bitcoin and gold in my opinion like
usual um but obviously those things are
usually very quick to recover just like
pretty much everything else after a
crash but my point is right everyone's
sitting here and we're all saying
including myself oh okay you know
clearly Bitcoin is going to be above
150,000 right we all think that or at
least I do you know I've been screaming
oh when bitcoin's above 150,000 my memes
are going to be a ridiculous bubble
prices right and so that's what we all
sit here that's what we all believe and
think about it every single four-year
cycle on bitcoin we never ran into a
market crash at this timing in the cycle
where we all think it's about to begin
what's the one thing that could stop our
you know fouryear cycle is and what
everyone would do is they'd be like oh
yeah our our fouryear cycle only was
invalidated because the stock market
crashed that's the only reason and it's
like I'm telling people in advance
anything that's going to [__] us is US
topping in October going into the
election and then bam things get worse
than we thought in the next month or two
you know as we once again set that top
in October and we start grinding down
into election I believe and here's the
thing I could be wrong about that I just
I don't think I'm going to be wrong
about that it just makes sense every
single time Market sets a peak in
October in the stock market and starts
going down into election you know what I
mean then the last three times soon as
November hits election hits up only from
there but you know that's what we're
hoping
for and I don't I don't think it by the
way you could be right you know you you
really could be we could have a local
correction at this phase I don't see
like a like a global top being in but
local correction like send it down I
don't I mean I don't see why that
couldn't happen you know I really don't
I mean it certainly could but I also
think it doesn't matter who wins the
election which some people think it does
some people think it it doesn't I think
it the trajectory will look different
but it doesn't really matter
historically whether a Republican or a
Democrat wins the election we get pretty
comparable returns both ways which I
think a lot of people probably wouldn't
agree with just be like I think a lot of
people think like oh Trump wins like
straight up Cala wins straight down I
don't I don't really agree with that
that's not what the data suggests to me
I don't know how you feel about it but n
i mean that's thing is that doesn't
really change the value of Bitcoin and
bitcoin's valued at what it is right now
given that both have well s almost equal
chance to win right now so Bitcoin is
perfectly like if Trump was 100% chance
to win then Bitcoin would already be
higher right now probably be at like
880,000 but it's 50/50 and that's why
bitcoin's priced at you know where it is
around 61 62 last I checked so it's like
these things are perfectly price given
all the information you know I don't
know hard to explain but it's like I
people are already positioned for Trump
win and people are already positioned
for camalo in
therefore you know the the the effect of
one of them winning like you like you
said it already ties into the value of
the asset I I don't know it's kind of
weird to explain but if that doesn't
make sense like it does yeah if you buy
a if you buy a house in Miami and maybe
this is wrong but is there a chance of
like a a tsunami in Miami if you have a
house on the beach I don't know but that
that's is do people consider their house
going underwater when they buy it close
to the beach yes and that's priced in
so you know what I mean yeah in
most mostly yeah my trading view is just
like glitching on me right now um yeah
actually let
me about the top for the S&P right now
which I believe it's it's at the very
least a local top now what happens right
if later on you guys are like oh no
Japan is blowing up we're starting to
see the effects of the interest rates
and now oh my God the Market's crashing
because look at this data or later on
it's like World War III began and and
everyone's like well usually war is
actually bullish for price right we'd
have to go back and do our own case
study there but what if the market
starts crashing and everyone's like oh
my gosh World War III started and see
the thing is what if there's someone
already higher up in the world who's
already planned these things to happen
and it's in the charts in the patterns
already but you won't realize it and
you'll start to blame that happening
later for why the Market's crashing and
then people will be like like oh well
it's only crashing because of Japan is
blowing up or it's only crashing because
of World War III you know and so that's
the thing I just play based off the
technicals the charts and not off of
future data but just based off the
patterns and stuff right now and so you
know this is a so it's such a 50-50 time
because you can literally look at a
pattern right now in the stock market
and you can be like well look at
2020 right and 2020 we go up only and
that's the thing I don't know what
happens 50 plus days out here I just am
confident in the next 50 days basically
that this top is in in October for the
stock market and we go down into the
election what I don't know is what
happens after the election because
typically the last three times we just
go up only after the election but I'm
not 100% sold that it's guarantee we
just go up only in November after the
election you know so that's the main
thing I'm I don't know the length of
this top like I said in my video to
anyone who watched it I said hey best
case
this is our top in the S&P for the next
50 to 150 days and we're already
recovering by late November December or
January we're already back to a new
alltime high in the S&P and we're
[__] going you know but you cannot
discount that three of the the six of
the last election years we had horrible
crashes and you may not see the reasons
now no one saw Co coming before it did
right and it hit the market no one saw
2008 coming or a few did and and it hit
so you're never going to see what it is
that crashes the market before it
happens usually anyways you know I'm
what do you think it would be right
because of course I know you're thorough
so it's like you're looking at the
technicals and you spotted a pattern
what do you think could act as that
headwin to propel that fractal into
actually
manifesting but that's the thing I
always say I always say I don't know all
the factors going on in the world I
don't know someone could some major
major player could blow up in Japan and
I don't even know who the [__] they are
right now right and then that causes a
domino effect so I don't know and I
really don't care right I just play off
the patterns and I know that okay this
is the pattern we have which gives me
extreme confidence that we're going to
dip going into the election for the
stock market and from there based off
the last three times we just recovered
up only in November but pray to God that
no no Domino you know effect hits
something that you don't you don't know
right now that you don't anticipate hits
because that's happened three of the the
six election years is it so crazy to
think like imagine Trump won and I saw
Alex Becker say this he was like imagine
the Democrats like rage quit and they
try to make Trump look bad as soon as he
wins you know what I mean and tank the
stock market so it looks like oh the the
economy's crashing because of trump you
know what I mean you can't predict that
you don't know who's in charge who's
pulling strings in this world and then
guess what if that happens who goes
belly up all of a sudden now someone in
Japan's going belly up someone over
there's going up and you couldn't have
seen all that [__] coming uh by looking
at data you'd only see that based off of
a pattern based off of a coordinated set
of moves from some very powerful people
that could have set that all up for
Trump to look [__] if he does win you
know what I mean so my whole thing is I
think it's very discounted the objective
fact is three of the last six election
years we had horrible Market crashes and
while everyone is sitting here and we're
so set and and confident that we're
about to run to 100K Plus what's the one
thing that could stop that is a market
crash right um and and and that would be
independent of Bitcoin but mostly
because of the stock market right and so
I just think it's heavily discounted the
chance of of actually things that we
can't really anticipate actually being
here in an election year because that's
what's happened so many times or at
least three of the last six times you
know
so yeah I I agree with and what everyone
would just be like oh it's only because
of War oh it's only because you know the
Democrats this oh it's because of this
because of that bro y'all say that after
you know what I mean the thing is the
pattern could potentially show us that
before all these things happen and also
you know based on this pattern we've
seen though you know okay basically
three of the six election years we just
go up only in November but three of
those election years we've had horrible
crashes too you know
so so I agree with you to be clear about
leaning into the technicals but I'd like
to if you're cool with it talk about
some of the technicals in crypto that I
would say kind of contrast a little bit
or disagree with some of the potentially
bearish technicals for S&P because
obviously the S&P 500's been going
straight up like look at you can just
put this down below for a brief second
like the s&p500 has been going I mean
vertical and Bitcoin has been doing the
opp opposite right so like these this
clear lot of people think that they have
to move together they're like haha you
idiot so if you're bearish on stocks
that means you think crypto must go down
it's like no you look at the the
reactions in last election years the
stock market drops in October and
Bitcoin has went up you know so but
where this affects bitco badly is if
once again this local top isn't just a
local top if it ends up turning into a
big top you know and that's the thing I
just believe right now it's a local top
but I'm not like I know there's a real
chance that this local top could be a
much bigger top than everyone thinks and
first off no one even thinks it's a top
right now in the stock market at all I'm
like the only one in the [__] world
right now saying hey hey hey watch out I
think there's some kind of top here at
the very least a local top which let's
pray it's only a local top because I
think people severely discount that
something way worse could happen that
you can't even anti ipate right now from
this top you know but God willing we
just go up only in November after
this yeah I I'm with you man I hope we
go up but I mean it it is important to
note like one thing I will absolutely
like pay respects to in in your analysis
here is that if we look at like the 2019
example right
Bitcoin was Bitcoin topped in June of
2019 by the way guys I not of the
opinion that this is where we're at
contextually like I think this kind of
already played out but at the same time
stocks were making higher highs Bitcoin
were make was making lows and then we
had like you know then the Black Swan
presented itself which was Co so I mean
I assume that's kind of what you're
referring to crash is like we're seeing
a Divergence between like Risk assets
being Bitcoin and Legacy being the S&P
500 SPX is in a vulnerable spot with
Bitcoin printing you know downtrends for
for six or seven months but you know
looking here here's what I wanted to
talk about too is like if if we're going
to talk about technicals right if we're
going to talk about leaning into the
technicals and then kind of letting the
news present itself and act as a
catalyst um and and by the way I agree
with that idea that like show me the
chart and I'll tell you the news right
this is our 2024 value area right here
so basically 70% of all of the
transacting for the entire year of 2024
so January through now the be very
beginning of OCT oober has happened
within this green box right here so
something that I think is important to
to recognize is let me actually put this
up I love this indicator here so I'll
move it up and and we'll make it look a
little bit different here just because I
want to talk about how I think that
bears have have gotten greedy like they
had seven months to you know really mess
with us and they just they just couldn't
get it done in my view and I'm going to
explain why and you know maybe crashy
agree or disagree we can we can talk
about that but um what this is right
here this is speaking of volume I know
you were talking about the significance
of you know
volume and what this indicator is
showing is relative volume oh why does
it keep moving back down sorry hang on a
second guys bear with me no pun intended
all right so what this is doing right
here is this is showing you relative
volume so it's basically when you have
volume that is way outside of your your
kind of mean okay and these arrows are a
little bit they need to be modified a
little bit here but I'm pointing to
these huge Cellars right here which
happen to be right at our 2024 value
area low so the most important level on
the chart so when I look at this as well
let me see I think I can add oops crap
okay I can't do it right here but
basically what this is showing is that
you had at these three events right here
so every every week every month of Q3
which is historically a really bearish
time for risk assets so July August and
September so first week of July first
week of August first week of September
what you had was statistical outlier
sell volume coming into the most
important level on the chart so the way
that I interpret this as a high time
frame swing Trader is Bears basically
had 90 days of attempted breakdowns to
start every single month of
Q3 and they basically got absorbed at
the most important level on the chart
which is our 2024 value area low they
got absorbed like all of this huge huge
cell pressure and again this is not
subjective like it's right here huge
capitulo cell volumes huge
liquidations and they got absorbed right
so when I look at this I go Bears got
greedy they had their opportunity to
sell this thing down three times and
right now this is the beach ball
underwater this is like we tried to
force a breakdown or we got stopped out
of our positions at these lows and now
it's time to run it back right like they
had their chance for you know they had
three huge chances and they couldn't get
it done right so this from a technical
perspective I look at this and I'm like
okay why would we go back down here
Black Swan aside right I will give you
that I will always give you the Black
Swan out and again I keep saying you I
don't mean like you but it's like I will
I will give everybody the Black Swan out
it's like of course you can't really
predict a Black Swan you could look at
the technicals and be like something
looks weird and then you find out about
it later but at this point when you have
90 days of huge seller you know
exhaustion and absorption at these lows
heading into historically bullish
quarter I have no choice but to be
bullish especially when we bring into
something you know the consideration of
this
chart so I spent some time making
this and I know you've probably seen
this we've we've talked about this but
what this is right here is basically all
of the three previous Bitcoin Cycles
overlaid on top of each other from bare
Market bottom through cycle top and I
have one of these for altcoins as well
so I'd love to look at that after
but what you have here is the Blue Cycle
2016 2017 cycle purple cycle was last
cycle when we topped at 69k and the
current one is in green I've also marked
out the Bitcoin
way too quick this was June of 2019 and
then we kind of mean revert and then we
overcorrected the downside because of Co
and then we mean revert right so it's
like you just can't fight your mean
right and they they always kind of find
each other then for example we spiked
early up in March right here probably
because the Bitcoin ETFs got ahead of
the previous two cycles which clearly
you know were synced up right over here
going into the having and then we spent
the last seven
months perfectly syncing back up with
our previous two cycles like look
at look at where we're at right here in
comparison to the previous two cycles
it's almost spooky you know it's almost
spooky where we come back perfectly
leading you know right between the
Bitcoin
all three cycles and then look at the
previous two cycles when things have
started to heat up you buy between the
having and the election if you're a
Bitcoin investor altcoins can you know
kind of navigate however they want and
then you typically rally you know
through the election you get your first
top bitcoin's first top was you know
right over here
64k um and then you know it drops so
like roughly from your bare Market
bottom Bitcoin will get its first top
you know 866 days from there so that
would take us maybe out into March end
of q1
so kind of front running sell and may go
away and then you buy the summer dip and
you come back for one more run it up and
I also have Bitcoin Vegas marked here
because like we joke about this all the
time there is like nothing more bearish
cyclically than a bunch of crypto nerds
spending money on strippers and tables
in Vegas so that's going to be a top bro
that's gonna be a local top for sure um
but yeah like I don't know what you
think about this chart crash but like I
look at this and I'm like I I I just
showed you like there's statistical
outlier cell volume every single month
in Q3 that got absorbed okay but here's
here's what I'll say about saying okay
three times we dropped Bears couldn't
get it done well same thing you can say
at the top when we tried to go higher
than 73k you had all the most bullish
news Bitcoin ETF eth ETF Black Rock You
Know crack rock this rock and and you
still couldn't go higher so you know the
same thing can be said to the upside
which of course here's the thing here's
what keeps me grounded more than
anything is the fundamental belief that
Bitcoin is going to be 150,000 plus
dollars and that the dollar over time
will lose value which makes all these
assets go up in price but it doesn't
stop us in you know from short-term
Corrections in the stock market for
example and like I said if we get a 4 to
eight% drop in the stock market well
based on 2020 based on
2016 it had no effect on bitcoin so
basically the way I said it in my video
and what I'm looking for is if Bitcoin
doesn't react negatively to a stock
market local top at the very least here
then we're on track to do what we've
always done but if we actually see
Bitcoin reacting negatively to what I
believe is a is a local top at the very
least in the stock market that's a bad
sign dude because if you were truly in
that bull run that we think we're in
Bitcoin should be bullish while the
stock market should be you know have a
top here you know what I mean and so for
now obviously I know last year as well
we dipped at the beginning of October
what I want to see now for all of us is
that Bitcoin will be bullish even if the
stock market will be will be R going
into election if that happens then I
think we're looking super good but you
can't deny I feel like it's a very bad
sign if Bitcoin would be bearish with
stocks going into election I think
that's a bad sign
yeah I agree with you like if stocks
pull back um and Bitcoin follows that's
you know obviously not going to be good
but yeah because the last two times
Bitcoin was completely unaffected by
stock market drop going into election
which is what it's like you're front
running the Bull Run it's like you're
front running okay it's like sell your
solar stocks sell your oil stocks
because we don't know who's going to win
the election but let's load up on
bitcoin instead it's kind of what it
feels like happened the last two times
but if it's like hey we're to election
we're uncertain sell Bitcoin just like
the stock market which is not what
happened the last two times that's a bad
sign you know to me that's shows like
more fear um of holding Bitcoin just
like those solar stocks just like a oil
stock going into election or whatever
stocks that someone may be overly
positioned in you know yeah I would
agree with that I don't know what you
think about eth here but I have some
thoughts i' I'd like to share and I
actually find it I I find it kind of
like spooky bullish honestly um but it
kind of does the same thing like every
cycle right like you have your blowoff
top and then you have a complacency
shoulder and then you have a bare market
reaccumulation and then you kind of do
the same thing so like for example this
was last cycle for eth like here's your
top way up here complacency shoulder
then you just nuke into a bare Market
here's your top last cycle or this was
two cycles ago this one's last cycle um
complacency shoulder and then you just
nuke into a bare market right so there's
this idea of like a region in which you
just generally can't lose otherwise
you're cooked right and that would be
the scenario that you're talking about
of if SPX pulls back and it drags crypto
down with it we might be cooked right
and I'm I'm acutely aware of like what
that scenario would look like it would
be horrible right my entire net worth is
in is in shitcoins so um here's your
bare market reaccumulation rate of last
cycle okay so this was eth over here in
you know
2019 after the complacency shoulder and
the drop okay and here's the current
cycle right here and then we're going to
zoom in and take a look at it this is
your bare Market reaccumulation range of
this cycle so you reaccumulate for like
a year and a half two years and then you
break out of it and then you retest and
then you get a bull market right I know
sounds easy right it's really not easy
but we're gonna talk about like some of
the similarities too so like we've
established these are the regions you
can't lose you couldn't have re-entered
you can't do this you couldn't have come
back down here re-accepted back into
this range this is a deviation because
then you're you're back in the range
you're completely fried just like right
now you can't come back down in here I
see a lot of people calling for like
$1,200 e you can't re-enter a 600 day
reaccumulation otherwise you're cooked
like you're just going to I don't agree
with that though you know I don't I
think you can come back into range and
then break back up and out of the range
again if if needed and obviously that's
I'm hoping to avoid that um and ideally
see this is what happens if the market
stock market tops here at 5800 but
crypto doesn't give a [__] right and it
just goes it just kind of stays here or
or is hopefully like the last two times
is bullish here we're looking super good
but like I said yeah if the stock market
Market actually drags eth down you know
with
it
um you know I I can see it and by the
way man I think it's more likely that
the stock market would drag ethereum and
altcoins down with it but not
necessarily Bitcoin as much you know so
I know usually Bitcoin and eth go
together but you know there eth has been
underperforming Bitcoin heavily so it's
something like where we could see
Bitcoin still around 55 to 65k but e
kind of just keeps losing dominance back
down like 1,800 for example if the stock
market starts pulling everything down
like a heavy weight with it you know um
that's something I I I think is really
possible too but I was going to show you
something let me go back to my chart
because I switched over to yours but I
just want to say that I disagree I don't
think there's anything actually bearish
about breaking back into a range
personally I don't think so I think I
think think we'd be cooked for a while
Black Swan aside like I think if you if
you go if you lose this
level and you're back into your bare
Market
range it's going to be a lot of pain for
a long time right like you you generally
need to hold this level and I mean I
don't really imagine how [__] all us
regular people would be potentially on
that like who does that open the opport
opportunity to buy in with size who
actually has size not us it's like black
rock and all these institutions that
would what as everyone of us is all like
liquidated or crying and dead they're
the ones buying it all cheap at that
point so I I don't think show you one
more thing of like let's just say it's a
bullish scenario from here right this is
your bare market like in my
view got to hold it l
you disagree but I think it's a God to
hold it level so you know we'll agree to
disagree that's fine I don't think you
got to hold anything man I think it's so
bullish when you liquidate a ton of
people to the downside and you get like
you know not the opposite of a god
candle right but to the downside like
those I think are so bullish so you
know I I think a nuke lower again would
just knock out so many people out of the
market that it's actually a good thing
personally
I mean how low do you think we would go
here like roughly well so in this
situation where stock market is able to
negatively impact crypto prices then I
think something down down a flush to
like 1,800 to 2100 is is great you know
but that's not but that's not
re-entering the range that's I mean
that's no it's piercing it that's so
bullish like that in my opinion right
now everyone's screaming up toober so
what Market goes down and everyone is O
so cocky uh about that price needs to go
up now October now like it has to go now
and so whenever you're over leverage
you're overly confident and you're all
in on one thing happening that's a lot
of times when you get killed so to me I
think a lot of people um you know I
think it's I think I just think it's a
perfect setup to kill a lot of people
man and you know it's uncomfortable to
hear possibly for some people but that's
usually what the market likes to do and
you know I would argue that the market
kind of did that the past six months
everybody was like YOLO got a lot of
people out but he topped in March bro
it's it's October you know it's like how
many more months of disaster you know I
mean look at bitcoin's still at you know
low 60s but I mean most altcoins I mean
the strong ones are fine
right but a lot of altcoins got
destroyed and didn't come back you know
yeah even though bitcoin's almost at the
all-time high still more people have
lost money than made money by far Mo
most people are like
really looking bad even though we're
right at the all-time high almost on
bitcoin you know so yeah no no doubt a
lot of people have gone
wrecked and but I just feel that right
now there's still
a lot of Cockiness that can get wiped
out with another strong move lower and
that's what personally here's the thing
I'm not even I'm not counting on that I
don't even want to see that happen I
want the market to go up for my net
worth for
yours but you
know obviously the last two presidential
elections Bitcoin was bullish in October
despite a red stock market that's what I
want to see we're not seeing that yet so
we'll see um I I find this interesting I
find this interesting I don't know
doesn't sound like this is what you're
expecting base case but you know this
was your bare Market Range High bare
Market Range High and we just kind of
kept carving out these choppy really
like awful higher lows within a range
and we're doing something kind of
similar right now now I will say you
know and here here's what I'll leave it
at okay I'm willing to entertain
anything like if you think we're going
to do this I know that you know how to
trade like it should be given you know
that scenario should be given respect
it's not a you're not prophesizing it
you're entertaining it right you're
being a Trader about it if we flip no
this thing is I just think that is so
bullish if we go and take out those lows
one more time and wipe out that
Cockiness out of so many people I think
that is the best for this market right
now actually and then up only from there
but um if we get up here though if we're
up in here bears are going to die bears
are going to lose everything if you
break out of this local range that we've
been in for two months at in my view the
got to hold it level God willing we're
there soon man you know but yeah that's
the thing is for now so far this month
we've been moving down with the stock
market and we better pray that this
changes like nowish um because if the
stock market is topped going into
election once again it makes sense
you're at all-time highs there's
election uncertainty who's going to win
and that affects the price of a lot of
stocks and sectors it makes sense you
would sell at all-time high going into
election with all that uncertainty right
so if the stock market does impact
crypto then I think you see e ethereum
come down undercut those lows again
right and that would be between 1,800
and 2100 and then hopefully from there
up only you know um so ultimately though
what's happened the last two elections
is crypto was despite a red October for
stocks so you know hopefully that kicks
in any second now but so here's what I
want to show you like I don't think
you're going to get that low I feel like
if you did go lower you would end up
doing something like this which is
actually funny enough this was
October yeah that's what I'm that's what
would be great
but that's not I mean that's not even
that like here
let's let's draw this here is people on
Leverage who have their stop losses
under the lows get badly wiped out and I
would say more people are long now than
they were there I remember there man
everyone and their mothers thought we
were going back down to 20K Bitcoin 18K
Bitcoin whereas now everyone thinks
they're going 100K so I think the pain
is a lot greater if we undercut this low
you liquidated a lot of people before up
only I just mean what's your sample size
on that like I'm not we I don't follow a
ton of people but I'm like crypto
Twitter's dead man like it's not like
there's a you know dude my whole feed is
so bullish it's insane so you know I I
mean of course and I'm part of the
problem it's like you know you said it
yourself you're all in on shitcoins so
am I and you know it just is right first
off there's a lot of similarities from
where we are today in the.com bubble if
you think about it where instead of
these do you know what the average you
know the average is the bubble all over
again no it's not do do you know what
the average PE ratio of a NASDAQ company
was during the Doom bubble okay what's
the PE ratio of a meme coin
bro
oh so I see what you're saying but
what's the market cap of like the all
coin indexes right like what's the
what's if you add them all together
right they're not they're like a nothing
they're not even a company you know like
it's it's not comparable if crypto
bubbled to a 10 20 trillion doll
valuation or something and I actually
agree with you like we're on the verge
of the cry crypto.com bubble right crazy
speculation most of them die and do
nothing and then a handful go on to be
Microsoft Apple Amazon Google but the
average earnings multiple of a NASDAQ
company during the com bubble was like
70 or 80 cumulatively like trading at
ridiculous valuations 3x what they're
doing right now so like there is in my
view no overlap from a valuations
perspective between how people are
valuing the current state of our economy
speculatively even including AI
companies all that kind of stuff
anywhere near what we saw with the dotom
bubble like the math just doesn't I
don't see that bro I don't see that and
like I get the comparison of like crypto
like what's the real intrinsic value
like how do you value these [__] coins I
mean most of them are worthless right
like they all promis that they're going
to like revolutionize everything and
then they're just ghost chains right but
I think that that's probably like three
or four years too early like you're
going to see a speculative frenzy on
blockchain and AI or blockchain and AI
together but like right now bro what's
what's the market cap of others like
others is 214 billion dude that's like a
tenth of the market cap of like one Mega
cap tech company you know I just can't I
can't get behind that is very different
what was see we don't know what was the
combined total market cap of all those
dot bubble stocks I don't know what it
was but um I think it's very similar
meme coins and crypto to the.com Bubble
it's very similar but okay let's put all
that subjective takes aside okay I am
hoping
that all of our bullish charts and all
of our bullish stuff is there and I have
believed 100,000% in all of them until
now my concern is this is what people
need to realize people are like don't
get bearish crash I'm not bearish on
crypto and and I'm not bearish on it
because it's down that's a g okay I am
bearish because the stock market has
been pumping to alltime high After
alltime High After alltime High
going into an election which
historically the tendency is you top in
October going into the election for the
stock market so that is what makes me
bearish not necessarily on crypto but on
stocks because a 4 to eight% slide in
the stock market shouldn't affect us
badly here in crypto but it's if that
top in the stock market evolves into
something much worse then the bull run
that we hope for and all expect that
would be [__] if the mark the stock
market ultimate topped here that's the
thing I know I I believe it's at the
least a local top but you never know if
a local top turns into an ultimate top
and that's what I'm telling people is
nobody in the world thinks it's even
possible that the stock market could
ultimate top I don't put the probability
as Mega High I can't have confidence
with certainty that it's a ultimate top
what I lean towards is a local top of it
takes us 50 to 150 days to get back to
the alltime High I mean we're we're
right at the alltime high right now dude
in the stock market I know but like
price Discovery innately is not a
bearish thing right I would say if you
start losing these levels then then yeah
but here's what I like I I know you you
already did this but like let's mark out
some dates of the US presidential
elections like right here on the S&P 500
chart like let's go back to the 80s okay
so November of
84 would have been I mean we're going
way back back right I don't know how far
back you went but like November of 84
was right here all right so we're just
going to Mark these all out with with
lines right here and then November of
88 so it would have been
right where are you August September
October November right
here we're just gonna I just want to do
this right I haven't actually done this
I I've only went back on the last 24
years but if you want to go back last 40
50 years we can do that too November of
uh it' be November of
92 so
this 80s and 90s was what up only right
so and we were coming out of a high
inflationary period which was the 70s
like we just came out of like let me
just if we're going to do the 80s and
90s then we should be doing the 70s and
60s and the 50s and the 40s too though
you know yeah don't want to spend three
hours [__] this up but yeah I agree
with you because that was the up only
Market which similar to now too 1990 so
November of 96 would be our next one
so uh November of 96 would be right
here and then uh November of 2000 would
be this one was [__] right
obviously com crash uh November of 2004
right here and then November of 2008
this one was cooked as
well wait that's 2007 sorry November of
2008 was right here so kind of close to
the bottom there that's
interesting um okay November of
2012 right there
roughly um November of market after
November not like most times it's
bullish besides 2008 2000 from what I've
looked at you know I haven't went back
40 60 80 years but the my main point in
the stock market is that September and
October you set a local top usually in
the market and then November is up only
after then you know what I mean that's
our base
case right up only once election
comes yeah so we BAS basically have 30
days cuz the election's November 5th I
believe November 5th
so I don't know I mean
I let I mean let's look if there's any
seasonal Corrections here like let's
literally Zoom way the hell in here and
go back like let me see what the months
leading into it were right so this
one kind of just like flat I guess
choppy dip before but that was in the
summer um 88 we had a big drop this was
in the November actually so a year
before so this was just kind of chop
into it right no well look look at the
observation I'm trying to make right is
before the line you go you're you're
dumping into the election right okay so
an 88 correction into it held held the
low only held the lows then up
only let's see here all right right here
kind of dipped and then recovered into
it kind of neutral just say whatever but
up
after um
96 little correction but we'll say this
one kind of went up into
it
um this one was cooked right dipped into
it popped into it dipped right into it
recession right but this was the.com
bubble over here and see this is
actually makes more sense to me this is
what I was talking about in the very
beginning where I was like you had this
High time frame break of trend you know
so like I feel more comfortable shorting
this rather than where you're saying
your bearish is like in my view even if
you're right bro like you're bearish up
here you know like we're right here no
glory no glory has ever come from
shorting a breakdown Glory comes from
the top man you know bro this is you
this is glory in my view bro I would
take this all day long dude look at this
thing that's Glory look at we nuked
that's Glory
I
mean I see I don't get bearish when
things break down I get bearish when
things are pumping and going up that's
my main principle that's how I shorted
the top of Bitcoin at 69k that's how I
was bearish on the S&P close to the top
like I don't get bearish on the way down
bro I get bearish when things are
pumping that's fair selling to Str thing
I don't I don't get bearish on crypto
when it's down here I only fear for us
all because the stock market looks like
absolutely horrendous to me see that's
the go go zoom out and look at the stock
market and people be like oh my gosh so
bullish and beautiful and I'm terrified
of the stock
market I go back no go back to like
where we are now right like the last
four or five years like oh my let's work
our way through we're almost there we're
almost there let's finish this and then
we we'll get to where we're at so yeah
that's a typical person though they're
like equities are so bullish and that's
when I'm scared man is just up only up
only up only I don't think you
comprehend how [__] manipulated the
stock market is bro like yeah but this
thing is the biggest Ponzi ever that's
why like it's so hard to make a living
being an equity the last the last 20
years every single election year every
single election year the last 20 years
stock market tops in October September
going into election that's what I'm off
of it's a local top I believe
all right so 2004 little drop into it
this was October moved up into it
whatever this one I mean I don't know we
were in the bottom of our great
financial Cris look September and
October you're dumping off into that
election and that is
yeah I mean this was just I mean this
was brutal though you know
that's yeah I mean I wouldn't have
wanted to sell anywhere down here but
yeah I mean I I see what you're saying
moving the months of September October
the last 20 years it's bullish going
into the election I mean I'm sorry
bearish going into election for the
stock
market now everyone always says yeah
this is a great example this is I think
what you're looking for right is like no
200 2008 2000 those right this is a this
is a big correction starting in
September bottoming out November after
the election and then it goes up right
yeah but now wait till like okay measure
how many days from the top there to get
back to the all-time high that's what
I'm saying 50 to 150 days from our high
here till we're back at alltime high
which actually we're almost at the
alltime high right now but like this is
where I'm calling it you know literally
right yeah that's what I'm saying is
okay we if we local top at the very
least in the stock market it takes us 50
to 150 days to get back to these highs
later but that's that's if we recover in
50 to 150 days you
know that's like the
best what was Bitcoin doing over here in
2016 it's going up I'm pretty sure
ramping yeah which is not right that's
what we're hoping Bitcoin will start
doing any second now you know so you get
that equities drop in October through
November and then they just ramp it
after the
election all
right yeah I mean okay I'll save these I
might look at these
later but yeah I just wanted to do that
like I hadn't put in the time like you
had on it you know
um us
elections all right what else should we
look at
anything if you want to look at altcoins
man I mean like if you look at a chart
like Brett like this is the thing that
is obviously like all coins look so
bullish overall you know Brett was
looking even more bullish whenever it
was actually going on that run right
there to like 1 billion you know it's
holding above the all-time highs now uh
that was at like what 900 mil over
there um you know and and this is what I
said in my my video so I was like so
conclusion am I selling any of my coins
I said no because even if we crash you
know yeah my my net worth Will nuke a
good bit but my life won't be changed if
we go lower but it will be changed if we
go higher right and the base case is
that we go up only starting in
November right you know how many times
I've shared your chart around showing
how we go up only in November usually
like I've shared that out on like 10
Twitter spaces now and every single time
I text people I'm like look at this up
only
November so that's the base case you
know that's what I hope for and that's
why I say local top in the stock market
is what I believe and just pray that
it's only a local top because if there's
something that would stop our Bull Run
that we all are counting on here it's an
ultimate top being in in the stock
market here you know so I said on my
Twitter I said I want to give myself two
chances to call the top in the stock
market one will be here I believe it's
at the very least the local top you
know because I I just I think when
nobody thinks it's
possible right once again I'm counting
on a local top at the very least but I
think this is one of those Prime Times
where you have a chance to get a an
absolute top in the stock market it's
happened you know you've had major
crashes three of the last six election
years this one has got so much at stake
like I said even if Trump wins you can
see them trying to make him look [__]
and try to crash the market or do
something against him to make him look
bad you know if Cala wins oh they you
know that that's supposed to be bearish
for the market which I don't believe
that either you know what I
mean I think with either presidential
candidate the market can crash um with
either presidential candidate the market
can pump
my thing is is just looking at the
patterns three of the last six election
years we've had huge crashes and I think
people
underestimate that it can happen and it
would happen independent of crypto if a
crash happens independent of crypto from
this 5800 point in in the S&P say
goodbye to our Bull Run for now you know
and that that's all it's not based off
of crypto that I'm making this
observation it's purely based on the
stock market that I think people should
be concerned
possibly you know I'm concerned for
myself like um and it wasn't it has
nothing to do with the crypto charts for
me it's purely based off of the stock
market you know I look at it and I say
man nobody thinks that we could in the
stock market absolutely nobody and you
know that's when you do top in the
market and it doesn't mean it's going to
be now right that's why I said like I
said in my tweet I want to give myself
two Chances with the stockk Market top
I'm going to give myself one here
because I'm very aware this can so
easily not be an ultimate top in the
stock market our base case is we go up
only in November that's what happens
after every election almost almost but
the few times that's not been the case
we've had horrific crashes after the
election to be honest you know
so I just can't look at it at these
charts and not be bullish here I like I
I'm not disregarding the scenario in
which stocks pull back and crypto Falls
with it like it it has to be entertained
like I'm not going to dismiss it at all
um but I mean looking at Brett here
right like it's it's a it's a leverage
bet on eth like you've talked about
we've talked about you know like look at
look at what happens here you know like
from this bottom right here you know eth
marks
up
40% and that triggers a huge rotation
into eth beta right same low right here
but Brett goes up 500 % you know so it's
like just and I don't have to tell you
this you own a ton of Brad right but
it's like if eth breaks up out of this
range like not only is everything Gonna
Fly but like you're gonna see not you're
not gonna see eth go up 40% you're going
to see it go up like 150 200% you're
probably gonna pressure the all-time
Highs at least and then you're I'm Gonna
Be Rich I'm Gonna Be Rich if we go up
should believe me I want to go up no I
know I'm I'm just showing the I fear for
us all though with the way the stock
market is I think it's just
severely not like people don't even
think it's possible and it's like to me
I think once again at minimum local top
but man I I see a real case where a
local top could evolve into something
much worse as we start actually making
our way lower in a stock market into the
election and then like I said Kamala
could win and we could go further lower
Trump could win and we could go further
lower these presidential candidates can
set off a domino on in either direction
of who wins you know what I mean like
you can once again you can see them
trying to make Trump look terrible yeah
but we did just go over like the past 10
elections like even if you do drop
locally typically especially when you
get a new president in office you get a
year of like really bullish conditions
right there's a lot of things that they
can do to further sort of engineer the
Ponzi to go up and they typically
utilize those tools at their
disposal even if you drop in September
October which I'm I'm open to so what's
so what's our base case though that is
that we go up only after November but if
you don't get your base case because it
seems that absolutely nobody in this
world believes anything besides that we
must go up which is if you've W if
you've followed me for the last year all
I've said is when Bitcoin is above 150k
[__] Bret and all my shit's going to
be 20x plus higher minimum right we all
count on one thing and what if the one
thing we count on doesn't come true at
time we need it or want it to come true
are you ready for that because if there
was something that's going to that's
going to mess us all up is it's being
overly dependent on one thing which is
that everything must go right and must
go up for us at now at this time and
little did you realize that the market
the stock market could be setting an
ultimate top and messing up your entire
plan to get rich right now and that's
what I'm just pointing out our base case
is we go up only in November but if our
base case doesn't come true what I could
see [__] us completely all of us
losing like 80% of our net worths is if
the stock market goes from local top to
Ultimate top
bro I don't know what that Catalyst
would be because I watched the need to
know the Catalyst you didn't know Co
before covid hit you didn't know that
the housing bubble was going to burst
like that until it burst and you didn't
know that the.com bubble well we were
probably too young at that time I know I
was to be sitting there being like Oh my
God these Doom stocks are overvalued I
must be bearish and they're goingon to
collapse like I was too young I was
[__] yeah
so you don't need to know the bro just
know that it could it could be there and
always be there it could
always I look at the technicals too and
I'm like we haven't broken structure yet
and I know that like that's being late
to the game but I'm like we have good
data and we haven't broken
structure bro I I'll just gonna say this
screw good data all right I was gonna
say F good data but I'm actually being
so levelheaded today screw good data I
don't give a crap about good data
because good data always comes at the
top man so you
know good data bad data I don't care
about the data all right no data then no
data but even if we data here's what I
say here's what I say I go I shift this
is my shift too though you know because
if you follow me I've been like a 100%
100% 100% hey man you know well mean I
here's the thing I'm 100% confident that
Bitcoin is going to be 150k
eventually and I'm 100% confident that
the meme coins as a ratio of Bitcoin
success will be astronomically higher
than where they are today so if you just
hold spot and you
chill and I
mean that's the tough part man if you
get one to two years of downtrend in the
S SMP we're we're [__]
man I I'm just I am scared because of
the stock market that's the only thing
that puts true fear into me right now
man but other than that yeah our base
case we just go up only in November you
know what I mean I've went all I'm doing
like it's like I'm shifting from 100% of
focus on this base case which is we go
up only in November and I'm going down
I'm toning it down I'm like 7030 now
about the base case and I'm not
discounting an ultimate top in the stock
market which is possible and and I know
how easily we can blow through this top
and just bull market continues right
like that's our base case 7030 but I
think there's a real chance a 30% chance
to me is a very high chance of a of a
top that destroys
us you say 30% chance that we get
destroyed I think yeah that's a very
high chance that scared me you know am I
going to sell [__] no because once again
my life doesn't change if we go down but
it does change if we go up like I said
I'm rich if we go
up I mean that's fair I'll still be able
to afford I eat steak every single night
for dinner and I drink strawberry
smoothies every single day I'm going to
be able to for that even if we knew you
understand the power of the strawberry
smoothie crash not study
it dude I'm G have enough for what I
care about really you know so going down
smoothies is that what you're were
saying theying smoothies and just train
man you know so I'm fine but it's just
like you know when everyone is 100%
confident and we all believe yes Bull
Run coming everything is going to
magically you know come together and
we're going to pump and everything's
going to be so beautiful and we're all
going to get rich it's like yes that's
what I've been saying that's what I've
been believing until well I've been
saying that and once again that's our
base case bro because as you can see
every single time almost after the
election we go up
only almost every single time the times
we didn't it was Financial I know that
you respect technicals and you're a
Trader the way I see this chart which is
others which is our shitcoin Mega
index we've been in a downtrend
for quite some time lower highs lower
lows for seven months and we
finally just for the first
time put in a
potential higher low Market structure
break to the upside higher
high with a higher
low that's bullish after 7 months that's
objectively that's
bullish it's hard to be bu that okay
fine let me show you my screen
man you beish this
chart no I'm not but okay higher highs
higher lows is is gay [__] let me tell
you why what does that even mean
bro okay go ahead okay go ahead I
already had this draw look at this I
remember everyone was saying higher
highs here for example they were saying
higher lows here here and then but the
difference is the difference is you had
a high time frame break of
structure you had a high time frame
break of structure and also those aren't
those are it's higher Highs but they're
higher lows they're sending it higher to
send it
lower that's a bare flag like if you
inverted that chart that's a bare flag
but but see as as bullish as we are on
that total chart you can say they're
sending it higher to send it lower there
too higher highs and higher lows is the
biggest [__] man and you know what
everyone does they're like oh it broke
my structure I must get bearish on the
retest here like 60% off the all-time
high they're like now I'm officially
bearish and then they're like it breaks
down you know here they're like oh no we
lost the range and they're like I must
short it right here so all this higher
low higher BS is all Bs man in my
opinion um so I mean and here's the
thing you come up
here higher lows higher lows higher lows
and then right here they're still gonna
say it's a higher low like it's all
[__] I'm stealing the screen back
this is this this is what you're talking
about but I inverted it okay this right
here this is not a good example like
you're in a
downtrend right here just like you are
here this is the scenario you gave but I
inverted it it's not even close to the
same this was moving up this one's
falling down they're they're building it
the exact same way
so it's I mean I can put you back on I
just want to show you like that's like
objectively that's not that doesn't make
sense like that's not the same pattern
like this inverted is the same pattern
but you're looking at one pattern I'm
showing you objectively how many times
people sit there and scream higher lows
and higher this
and it's just goes down right where like
show me on bitcoin or
SPX I just showed you on bitcoin where
people are still thinking it's higher
highs and higher low so when you look at
a higher high or a higher low it's
subjective on what you want to consider
the higher high or the higher low
because look here yeah in this range of
30k to 48k there's making higher highs
and higher lows and then in hindsight
everyone's like oh it was a be flag but
in the moment people are like oh yes yes
guys after months of downtrend we're
finally making our first higher lows and
our higher highs we're looking really
good guys and then it collapses on them
so okay this is this is the difference
in the structure okay this is the
difference in the structure you were
technically you're right like this right
here is an uptrend right like there's
your low there's your high higher low I
don't know we'll just oh my gosh let's
go all in bullish Aller low and then you
broke structure right at this point now
you have to be cautious because you
broke structure this is this is Supply
we never had a structure like this on
others right like they're sending this
lower in my opinion to send it higher so
for example if we came back up to
here after falling for this long like I
mean you can see the difference in these
structures like this one is clearly
sending it
lower right here like this is falling
and this one is rising right but if for
whatever reason we came up here and we
did this and then lost it then that's
super bearish right if we did that we
didn't there was no distribution here
there was no distribution and
furthermore this one was coming back
into retest like high time frame Supply
right here where this structure is
actually coming back into to retest High
time frame demand like this is the big
difference like they're nothing alike in
my opinion this one was retesting Supply
deviation trap this one's retesting
demand and they're falling the exact
opposite way from each other I don't
know if you would disagree but I'll I'll
share my screen of another example then
um like I said for me higher highs
higher lows it's not analysis that I
will ever ever like look at really like
cuz do you remember this downtrend man
in the S&P for example course yeah I
flipped I flipped bullish on the S&P by
the way right here okay it's on my video
and I had it pulled up yesterday when I
was making a video I was literally like
screaming at some guy's YouTube comment
and he's like zoom out of the S&P chart
and do you not see those lower highs
right so lower high lower high lower
high lower high and so everyone in their
mothers thought oh lower highs lower
lows lower lows lower lows everyone in
their mothers right here thought okay
we're going to Nuke lower to sub $3,000
when we put in that bounce right below
where you flipped in your circle that
was a higher low that's where we're at
right now for crypto bro that is a
perfect example it literally looks the
same too right there yeah notar on that
chart right I'm not bearish on that
chart at all but I'm just saying I don't
use higher
highs and higher lows as analysis
because actually what most people do is
see I'm betting that we're going to
break out here while other people are
betting we're going to break down so
someone has to be wrong so that someone
has to be right I'm not bearish on our
altcoin chart there at all like I said
our base case we go up only soon in
November really we should start going up
only now but where is it I'm waiting for
it it's almost here bro any day any day
now any
day here let me let me do this okay
we're coming back to me now ready okay
this I love this example that you just
gave right here I love it because that
is literally what we're doing it's very
similar to that yeah it's great very
similar that's a thing though right you
realize what I've been saying is that if
if I never looked at the stock market
I'm I'd be I'd have zero fear in me
right if I didn't look at the stock
market I only looked at crypto my only
fear stems from the stock market not
from crypto
charts right but I'm telling you also
there's not a reason to be afraid of
equities right now when they if they
break structure then let's talk about it
right and if you happen to spec the top
I mean that's skill that like I don't I
mean I don't have I can't do that I
can't spec the top before there's a
catalyst or bad data or a break of
structure I don't know you're a magician
if you do it you're literally a magician
I don't see the reason that I believe
it's far more likely to be a local top
than an ultimate top in the stock market
right I I am just the main base case for
me is we top into the election right and
then we go up only after the election
well what I'm showing people is that
don't
discount that your local top could turn
into an ultimate top things could get
worse than we thought and things can get
in the way of you getting rich right now
when you want it you know
I mean I can't believe me I'm bullish
I'm bullish on crypto charts my fear
comes from the stock
market so yeah I mean this is so this is
where you got bullish like right in here
this blue area and that was a good spot
even if it was a hair early before this
drop because it's like you mean you see
the shift of trend here where like
you're putting in these
lows and then suddenly you get these
higher lows for the first time in a year
that's exactly what we're doing right
now with crypto and I know we're we're
saying one and the same thing you're
just worried about
equities but I can't fade this like
we're right here right
now so you know what this all ties into
is that stocks still top in October but
we go up only you know regardless if
stock market has a local top here that's
what this points to I'm cool with
equities locally pulling back giving you
your five or six% cor also I am also
cool with equities locally topping and
pulling back as long as that local top
doesn't evolve into something much worse
you know that's what I'm saying is if
this local top turns into something
that's not a local top because that's
the thing I at minimum believe it's a
local
top you know so just I'm just saying man
three of the six election years really
bad [__] has happened in the market for
stocks and if really bad [__] happened
in
stocks you know say goodbye to our
crypto for now you know but I'm not I'm
not betting on that I'm not counting on
that if that was what I was betting on
or counting on I would have
sold you realize that right like I am
Allin long but I'm telling everyone if
there's something that's going to get in
the way of us having this bull run that
absolutely everyone is counting on it's
an equities crash that no one expects or
anticipates from this local top that
could actually turn into ultimate top
but God gosh dang I believe it is a
local that's like saying bro every time
SPX is in price Discovery oh something
could happen and blow it up it's like I
don't know what that would be like what
maybe you mentioned it in your video but
like what what is it going to be like
what what's going to Nuke it you know
like who's going to implode like where
are the mortgage delinquencies you know
where are the layoffs where are the
initial claims right where's the
inflation Rising that all happens later
bro that all happens later all
right I'm not sitting there counting on
the market to collapse I am in fear
telling everyone hey guys there's a
chance that we're all [__] if this
local top isn't just a local top in the
stock market and while nobody even sits
there and considers it everyone
including myself has been cocky that
crypto is just going to go up and up and
up and we're going to be above 150k soon
well we're all going to be poor okay
that's all I'm saying if this local top
turns into something worse than that as
we actually start to go down into the
election all
right fair
enough fair enough I hope that we don't
nuke that's all I'll say because I'm
looking at the structure and this looks
really really constructive it looks
incredibly bullish that's why I said if
I never looked at stock charts I
wouldn't have an ounce of fear in me I
have fear not because of crypto charts
only because of where stocks are
man all right well I hope you're wrong
but fading you has never been something
that work well for a lot of people so
but what am I wrong about because I'm
not putting my money on a market crash
my money is Allin long here's the thing
it's a win-win winwin for you because
either you call the Pico top of the S&P
500 and it's legendary or everybody gets
rich and you're wrong and nobody cares
like it's there's no downside here like
I see the vulnerable setup and I don't
think you're calling like a fiveyear
recession or something but I'm like
there's not really downside like there's
a vulnerable setup it's worth noting and
if it doesn't work you actually make
more money and so do your followers so
it's like win-win right either you're
hedged and you warn people or like we we
get rich so no but I'm not hedged like I
only have don't you no no no I have an e
that's what you didn't let me finish my
sentence I'm going to say I'm not hedged
enough
because you
know if the Mark if the stock market
topped there badly but this this is what
I'm saying you know now I should have
just kept everything to myself I should
have just let everyone get [__] if we
got [__] you know what I mean because
what am I doing ultimately with my money
I'm Allin long right but what I'm saying
is local top and the stock market going
into election we better hope that that
doesn't affect the price of crypto it
hasn't the last two
times and then hope that a local top
doesn't evolve into a ultimate top
because I could see it happening
man
okay all right bro we've been going for
about two hours anything else we should
talk about quickly I feel like two hours
is pretty good but yeah if you have any
if you have any all coins you want to
cover because ultimately look at the
altcoin chart right here right it's Mega
bullish what's our base case we go up
only starting in
November you know and I and I say what
if there's and I I'm saying here local
top but have fear of a ultimate top in
the stock market is what I'm telling
people have fear of it because it is
really possible it's not what I'm
counting on it's not what I'm betting on
but the pattern is there and it should
strike fear into all of us because if
the stock market ultimate top there when
no one expects it when nobody believes
it could even be possible we're all
going to lose 80 to 90% of our net
worths that would suck I don't know what
else to say that would suck but yeah I
mean I don't really have like I mean I
can share what I'm long you already know
like I'm I'm just long like Pepe Brett
Andy like I like wolf like I'm into the
boys club I know you're just more Focus
on Brett um you know and rightfully so
but I don't really even need to get into
him like because it's like it this chart
right here like others is the others is
the rising tide that lifts All Ships
right like if this chart on the left
breaks up it's turn your brain off
season you know it's like everything
pumps so it's like this is the only
thing that matters is like can Bitcoin
go into price Discovery and can this
others chart hold this breakout and
actually move higher and if so you're
you're going to be able to basically
long any altcoin you want there's going
to be outperformers of course and I
think that I'm allocated in them as I'm
sure yeah you would agree you are as
well crash but it's like you know we
just need the Tailwinds of Majors doing
well we need eth back above 3K we need
Bitcoin pushing 70 to 80k and then it's
alt season but you know you know what
though before we end the stream this
something came to mind for me yeah um
okay let me know if you can see my
screen y you're up yeah okay so take a
look at Bitcoin over the stock market
and eth over the stock market
so okay first off pretend like you don't
even know what this ticker is according
to a lot of you guys who look at higher
lows and breakdowns and retest of
structure is this the E spy chart like e
divided by spy okay yes so if you didn't
know what the ticker was though freaking
all of you guys who be shorting this
right now right I bet you 99% of you I
you know so this is why this brings me
into my point of look if you look at
Bitcoin versus the stock market
though look Bitcoin didn't break that
Trend eth did right
so you know based off how a lot of
people look at it this is why I believe
that if the stock
market underperforms
here that ethereum and altcoins would
suff
and Bitcoin for example could chill
between 55 and
65k but you know what would actually
struggle would be ethereum and altcoins
even more you know so yeah just look at
that you know and that's what I'm saying
if the stock market negatively affects
our prices last two election years
Bitcoin didn't give a [__] if the stock
market was dropping in October right but
so far for now this month the stock
market's performance has been affecting
us you know so if it continues to keep
up you
know then I I think Bitcoin is just
going to keep outperforming for
now um and and it's ethereum and
altcoins that would struggle the most if
if we stay tied to stock market price
action all right that's fair that's fair
I just will show you one chart okay
here's ethusd at that same time frame
you can save
it it can be saved yes but that's what
I'm saying well but here right now
according to a lot of you guys you'd be
like oh it broke structure and it's
retesting it as bearish right whereas
there it didn't retest or anything it
just went through it again you know what
I mean that's why
personally I don't care so much about
like these what people say oh we broke
structure we broke this we broke that
because I've seen so many times
s how uh you know you break structure
and then you just go up only for example
or oh we're breaking out price Discovery
and that's the top you know Caspa just
did it Bitcoin did at
69k you know what I mean so many times
you're breaking out price Discovery you
broke the the you left behind the old
structure and it's the top oh you're
breaking down if we lose this level
lights out and it's the bottom you know
so I don't care about breaking structure
retesting this structure and stuff you
know what I mean do you do you think
that this is a bull this is Bitcoin SPX
like do you think that this is a bullish
looking chart or a bearish looking chart
like the way that you look at it this is
bullish this is
bullish right and that's doesn't matter
what eth looks like because you know
that like all we're trading whether it's
Brett or like like others or E like all
we're doing with anything is trading
Bitcoin through different Vehicles like
you know that it's it's if Bitcoin goes
up then it will drag up eth and soul and
everything else Kicking and Screaming
whether it likes it or not you know so
I'm like I don't really care about the
eth structure what I care about is how
Bitcoin looks against guess against
these pairs like SPX or against the
dollar because if Bitcoin looks good
it's gonna here's the thing if Bitcoin
just keeps going here without breaking
out but ethereum keeps underperform in
the stock market while the stock market
dips four to eight percent then ethereum
can can go to what low right while
Bitcoin kind of maintains where it's at
roughly yeah I
mean weird bottom look at that top in
July by the way right so if you put a
horizontal line there no not in 2023 I
think top of July yeah yeah that
midpoint so how many people would be
like oh no ethereum broke back into the
range oh no it broke into the structure
you know see I don't care about that but
hey remember you were showing me that
ethereum chart earlier in the Stream how
hey if ethereum broke back down below
into the range you know it would be bad
well that's what it's done here in the
S&P or versus the S&P but I don't think
I still think ethereum is gonna
absolutely destroy and crush the stock
market when we're uh in our bull run you
know yeah I mean I I get it I get it you
know I just think it's like not to
dismiss this because like it should be
noted of course you know like this is
this is clearly a valid trend line like
this is how I view the trend line we're
just sitting kind of right below it it's
like one two three four are you in log
or are you in uh this is linear yeah
okay I was on log so you know then
that's another thing on log for me it
looks different yeah it looks like oh no
we broke it we retested see I don't care
about this [__] because look you just
did it on linear scale and it wasn't
like that so to me I don't care because
actually I'm bullish on that I'm not
bearish on that overall you know I mean
I think you're far closer to a bottom in
ethereum's performance versus stock
market than you are well now you just
flipped it so it made me feel weird but
you're far closer to a bottom there than
you are going way lower so you see like
I'm bullish on ethereum versus the stock
market except I know that if it keeps
kind of underperforming for now a little
bit under here while the Market's going
down 48% you know that looks like
ethereum going down to 1,800 in that
case
yeah all right let's call it here this
has been a great stream guys whoa that's
close all right guys thanks so much for
being here um I say crash and I do these
every few months um so thanks for tuning
in had a good time um hopefully we don't
lose it all and my background doesn't uh
my background doesn't happen because
that background is going to happen right
there if equity's nuke so let's hope
that we don't get that crash thanks for
uh thanks for doing this man I'm happy
we were able to put this together kind
of quickly last minute and guys if you
don't follow crash and you're on the BB
Channel definitely give him a follow
he's got some awesome plays I know we
talked a lot about equities but he
really is like a crypto guy like he's
got a lot of really great plays um he's
kind of a meme coin Legend if you don't
know him I feel like most of you
probably do know him but like he's uh
he's one of like the top meme coin guys
for sure that can follow and I know you
guys at BB love love meme coins so
definitely give him a follow um and I
guess if you don't follow me follow the
BB YouTube channel and also my Twitter
but yeah guys thanks so much for being
here crash appreciate your time bro and
we'll probably maybe we'll slip in
another one before the end of the year
who knows you know good time to check in
sounds good man talk later all right see
you guys thanks
[Music]